Max Lewis

Aspiring Software Engineer looking to learn and create impact.

Lockport, Illinois, US | +1 (815) 708-4410 | mlew3223@gmail.com

https://github.com/mslew | https://www.linkedin.com/in/maximuslewis/ | https://www.maxlewis.dev/

Computer Science Graduate

I am a recent computer science graduate with substantial hands-on experience with Python, Java, JavaScript, and Full Stack development. Perceptive problem solver with an innate ability to learn quickly and apply previous experience with original solutions to solve problems.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Lewis University

May 2023

- GPA: 3.82/4.0, magna cum laude.
- Dean's List: all four years.
- Outstanding Student Employee of the ECaMS Department for the 2022-2023 school year.
- Dr. Stephany Schlachter Excellence in Undergraduate Scholarship Award Finalist.
- Schmidt Family Foundation Grant for Academic Excellence 2020-2023.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java (Proficient), Python (Proficient), JavaScript (Proficient), SQL (Proficient), HTML (Proficient), CSS (Proficient), Go (Familiar)

Technologies: React, Node.js, Express.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap 5, Sass, Svelte, Microsoft Azure, Google Firebase

PROJECTS

QuizMaster | https://github.com/QuizMasterInc/QuizMaster

Jan. 2023 - May 2023

- Designed, as part of an Agile Scrum team, a comprehensive quizzing application to keep users' minds sharp on various topics.
- Redesigned and modernized the front-end application from HTML/CSS/JavaScript to React and Tailwind CSS
 optimizing the user experience.
- Onboarded and mentored Juniors to develop new features and take over maintenance ensuring project continuity.

In Theaters | https://github.com/mslew/in-theaters

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Built an Android application, in Java, that allows users to see new movies in theaters that week.
- Integrated Google services for ticket purchases, providing a holistic ticket-buying experience.

An Agent-Based Model of Clostridioides difficile in Healthcare Settings

June 2022 - May 2023

- Lead a team for the development of an agent-based model built with NetLogo.
- Tracks infections of Clostridioides difficile due to environmental conditions in a healthcare setting.
- Forthcoming publication in the Journal of Mathematical Biology, 2024.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Building Custodian, Will County School District 92

Aug. 2018 - Present

- Maintained building cleanliness per district standards for an assigned 8 classrooms.
- Collaborated with staff members to establish well-running classes and school events.

ECaMS Tutor, Lewis University

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

- Advised students in Computer Science and Mathematics.
- Collaborated with professors and tutors to better aid students.

AWARDS AND ACCOLADES

MAA Mathfest – Janet L. Andersen Award for Outstanding Undergraduate Research

2022

• The Annual Meeting of the Illinois Section of the MAA – Outstanding Undergraduate Research

2023